# **Edward McMillan**



djmcmillan93@gmail.com



678-951-5143



linkedin.com/in/dj-mcmillan-56400028



https://www.djmcmillan.com/

# Summary

Currently a full-time employee at Playmakers Athletic Footwear & Apparel. Worked in a variety of roles including:

- 11 years in teaching & coaching
- 7 years in management
- 5 years in web development

Utilized technologies & API's such as React, MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, Shopify-Plus, AWS, Pusher, Twilio, and many more to help drive eCommerce sales from less than \$0.5 mil/year to over \$15 mil/year over 3 years.

My Portfolio: dj-mcmillan.herokuapp.com

# **Experience**



### **Web Developer**

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Apr 2018 - Present (4 years 9 months +)

Created and implemented dozens of custom-built applications that have allowed both online and instore operations to scale efficiently and effectively.

Oversaw eCommerce growth from less than \$0.5 mil/year to over \$15 mil/year over 3 years

# Team Leader (Manager)

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Jun 2016 - Present (6 years 7 months +)

Utilized leadership and connection skills to develop staff and prepare them for successful careers, both at Playmakers and beyond

### Clinic Outreach Coordinator and Instructor

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Jan 2015 - Present (8 years +)

Developed, coordinated, and taught hundreds of non-profit health & wellness-based outreach clinics

# Good Form Running Clinic Instructor and Guest Advocate

**Tortoise & Hare Sports** 

May 2014 - Jan 2015 (9 months)

Instructed Good Form Running Classes, creating a fun and informative environment where learning best thrives

### 🀎 Good Form Running Clinic Director

Big Peach Running Co.

Oct 2013 - May 2014 (8 months)

Perpetually developed curriculum for the Good Form Running Clinics in order to remain on the cutting edge of gait retraining

Recruited, trained, and developed Good Form Running Coaches to ensure that they provided the best possible experience for the students

Coordinated and scheduled Good Form Running clinics both at the stores and at various events outside the store



### 🌦 Point of Sale System Coordinator & Guest Advocate

Big Peach Running Co.

Apr 2012 - May 2014 (2 years 2 months)

Accurately entered and received dozens of product orders each week, correctly including any applicable vendor discounts

Punctually added product SKU's and UPC's into the point of sale system, including product descriptions, categories, wholesale costs, retail costs, and margins

Comprehensively gathered information from each guest in order to make adequately educated decisions on footwear needs

Developed relationships with guests to produce an unparalleled experience

Assisted in the transition and implementation of the new point of sale system at each store, writing Excel VBA code to convert and consolidate SKU's



**TNT Fireworks** 

May 2007 - Jul 2010 (3 years 3 months)

Conducted pre-operations analysis to estimate necessary workforce, resulting in maximum operational efficiency

Oversaw the financial aspects of everyday operation, minimizing unnecessary expenditures and maximizing profits

Kept precise financial books in order to accurately determine outflows, inflows and gross profits Managed the general operations of the tent in order to most effectively capitalize from the sales, resulting in an increase in gross profit from 2009 to 2010 of 83%

### **Education**

# Michigan State University

Coding Bootcamp, Full Stack Coding

2022 - 2022

Gained desirable technical skills and invaluable industry knowledge to accelerate my journey into Development.

### 🛂 Georgia Tech Scheller College of Business

Bachelor of Science, Management; Pre-Law

2007 - 2012

BSM Concentration in Operations & Supply Chain Management.

Scholarship Athlete (Cross Country/Indoor & Outdoor Track).